# Marco Spano

07712439273 | marco\_spano@hotmail.com

#### **▲** Profile

I am a self-taught Front End Developer and I am passionate about programming. I decided to change career and turn my passion into profession. To achieve my goal, I spent last 6 months broadening my knowledge and catching up on the latest web development trends and technologies. I also utilized this time, to build apps using the latest React features and libraries. What I am looking for is the opportunity to learn and develop new skills and work as a part of a team.

I have been working as a manger of a large team in one of the busiest London hospitals for the past 7 years. This helped me to develop my organisational and problem solving skills.

### **E**xperience

Ħ 12/2019 - PRESENT ♡ LONDON, UK

### **Front-End Developer**

- Voluntarily helping a newly-funded start-up business to develop its commercial Website, for self-educational purposes. Includes coding in Javascript, HTML 5 and CSS/SASS.
- Building Apps using the latest technologies (React.Js + hooks, Marerial UI, RESTful API)

Ħ 11/2013 - PRESENT ⊙ LONDON, UK

### **Deputy Support Service Manager Interserve Group Ltd**

- Responsible for managing 200+ members of staff
- Working following tight deadlines and under pressure in a fast paced environment
- Responsible for liasing between different departments within the organisation as well as external clients, such sub-contractors, members of the Trust
- Responsible for organizing the daily sanitization of the hospital
- Training staff (Health & Safety, Infection Control, COSHH).
- Investigating Heath & Safety incidents/accidents and reviwing Health&Safety procedures.
- Auditing another hospitals in order to find ways to optimize the service

### **Experience**

Ħ 01/2001 - 08/2002 ♥ SINNAI, ITALY

## PC Technician Assistant IT Solution

 Responsible for installing and testing PCs, fix performance issues, diagnose hardware-related problems, repair PCs in offices, homes and in any place or work environment with installed PCs

### Education

苗 12/2019 - PRESENT 🖓 ONLINE, UK

### Web developer Udemy

- Specialities: HTML/HTML5
- CSS/SASS
- SemanticUI
- Responsive Design
- Flexbox
- CSS Grid
- Bootstrap 4
- DOM Manipulation
- Javascript
- HTTP/JSON/AJAX
- React
- Git + Github
- Command Line
- NPM

苗 07/2020 - PRESENT 🖓 ONLINE, UK

# TypeScript Udemy

□ 04/2000 - 04/2002 
 ○ CAGLIARI, ITALY

### Web Designer ISNETW Informatics school

Creating and maintaining websites with HTML 4.1 and Dreamweaver

Ħ 04/2000 - 04/2002 ♥ CAGLIARI, ITALY

# CED Operator ISNETW Informatics school

• Certificate in PC Hardware, Windows OS and Office Package (Word, Excel, Access, Power Point, Outlook)

### 

## (i) PROGRAMMING SKILLS

JavaScript HTML 5 CSS/SASS ReactJS Git

### (i) OTHER COMPUTER SKILLS

VS Code Sublime text 3 Adobe Photoshop

### (i) LANGUAGES

English Full
Italian Native
Spanish Elementary
French Elementary

## # Hobbies



Exploring other countries



Capturing moments



Learning new technologies



Football



Playing Piano